Frank Ormsby papers, circa 1967-2004
Emory University
- The Honest Ulsterman literary materials, 1967-1990, Series 2; Boxes 5-16; OP 1 - 5
  - The Honest Ulsterman author files, 1968-1996, Subseries 2.2; Boxes 7-12; OP1-3
    As editor of The Honest Ulsterman, Frank Ormsby kept detailed files on a host of individual authors. These files contain correspondence, often of both a personal and professional nature, sent to Ormsby or to the magazine. Also, many individual writers' manuscript or typescript submissions to the magazine have been preserved here. The author files include not just individual poems or prose pieces but larger sequences, collections, or pamphlets to be reviewed by the editor. Additional materials include interviews, worksheets from sessions of the Belfast Group, assorted promotional materials, and published reviews or essays about particular authors. Significantly, though these files originally served as the editor's record of contacts with a particular author, Ormsby maintained them even after leaving The Honest Ulsterman. This is especially true with the Seamus Heaney files that contain many reviews of Heaney's works published as late as 1995. The Heaney files are also notable for their collection of Heaney's published literary journalism from the late 1960's and early 1970's. Other substantial files pertain to Ciaran Carson, Gerald Dawe, Michael Foley, Robert Greacen, John Hewitt, Michael Longley, Derek Mahon, Medbh McGuckian, Paul Muldoon, Tom Paulin, Carol Rumens, and James Simmons.
    Author files are arranged alphabetically by author. Correspondence is kept in one or more dated files. Individual works are preserved in discrete folders and listed in alphabetical order.
    - Adcock, Fleur, Correspondence, 1977-1984 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Arts Council of Northern Ireland, Correspondence 1983-1996 [includes some Carson correspondence; no Longley materials] (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Arts Council of Northern Ireland: Receipts, 1989-1995 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Buchanan, George, Correspondence, 1972-1983 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Buchanan, George, Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Buchanan, George, Poetry: “Ballygalley Head,” and “Psychic Suicide,” TS (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Buchanan, George, Poetry: “Christmas,” TS (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Buchanan, George, Poetry: “A Church By the Water,” TS (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Buchanan, George, Poetry: “The Dead,” and “Magda and a Group,” TS (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Buchanan, George, Poetry: “Limavady Verses 1946,” TS (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Buchanan, George, Poetry: “Old Stag,” TS (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Buchanan, George, Poetry: “Privacy,” TS (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Buchanan, George, Poetry: “Prophet,” TS (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Buchanan, George, Poetry: “Teenager,” TS (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Buchanan, George, Poetry: “W.B. Yeats,” TS (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Buchanan, George, Prose: “The Autobiographies,” TS (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Buchanan, George, Prose: The Umbra, TS [autobiography]; includes ALS from Buchanan, 20 April 1976 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Correspondence, 1970-1982 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Correspondence, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Poetry: The Insular Celts (1973), pamphlet mark-up (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Poetry: The Lost Explorer (1978), TS (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Poetry: “After the Exile,” TS (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Poetry: “Cyclist,” “King’s Lynn,” “Wheel,” MS; includes ALS from Carson (undated) (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Poetry: “The Death of Colmcille,” TS (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Poetry: “The Irish for No,” TS (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Poetry: “Liadan’s Love for Cuirithir,” TS (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Poetry: “Moving In,” TS (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Poetry: “Serial,” TS (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Poetry: “Sisters,” TS [variant title: “Obituaries”] (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Prose: “Interview with Ciaran Carson,” TS and published version in Linen Hall Review (spring 1991) (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Correspondence, 1976-1993 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Correspondence, undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Poetry: Sunday School Poems (1991), TS (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Poetry: “Alba,” TS (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Poetry: “Backward Look,” TS (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Poetry: “Chronology,” TS (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Poetry: “Distances,” TS (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Poetry: “Do Not Walk on Graves,” TS (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Poetry: “Double Exposure,” TS (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Poetry: “Ghosts,” TS (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Poetry: “Interstices,” TS (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Poetry: “Leda,” “Monolith,” “The Spiritualist,” “Territory,” TS; includes TLS from Dawe (undated) (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Poetry: “Shades of Alexander Park,” TS (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Poetry: “Sunday Walk at Ross,” TS (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Poetry: “Vigil,” TS (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Poetry: “Vista,” TS (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Dunn, Douglas, Correspondence, 1974-1984 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Dunn, Douglas, Translations from the Polish of Piotr Sumner: “Drop,” “At Least I See It That Way,” “Cavafy,” “Recently,” “Arrival,” “Smiling with reconciliation,” “The man…,” “What You Need To Do,” “Before Sleep,” “Exiles,” “In these same rooms,” TS (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Durcan, Paul, Correspondence, 1977-1980, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Ewart, Gavin, Correspondence, 1968-1984 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Ewart, Gavin, Correspondence, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Ewart, Gavin, Poetry: “Anti-Christmas Poems,” TS [including: “Advice for the Winter,” “The Reason Why,” “Sonnet: People Who Love Abstractions,” “Two Poems for Bad Children,” “The Unforeseeable,” “The Young Lady of Herm”] with ALS from Ewart, 2 December 1986 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Ewart, Gavin, Poetry: “Double Haiku: Singers,” TS (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Ewart, Gavin, Poetry: “Experience Hotel,” TS (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Ewart, Gavin, Poetry: “In the Divorce Court,” TS and “Penal,” TS (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Ewart, Gavin, Poetry: “John Reginald Halliday Christie,” TS (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Ewart, Gavin, Poetry: “The Little Girl Writes a Sonnet About Her Dead Cat,” TS (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Ewart, Gavin, Poetry: “Miss God,” TS (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Ewart, Gavin, Poetry: “On the ‘A’ Level Syllabus,” TS (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Ewart, Gavin, Poetry: “On the Spot,” TS (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Ewart, Gavin, Poetry: “The Relaxed Sunday Morning,” TS (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Ewart, Gavin, Poetry: “The Return of the Hero,” TS (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Ewart, Gavin, Poetry: “Sonnet: The Carpet,” TS (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Ewart, Gavin, Poetry: “Three Poems” [including TS of: “The Lives of the Poets,” Soldiers’ Song,” “Ending”] (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Fallon, Peter, Correspondence, 1969-1984 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Fallon, Peter, Correspondence, 1989-1996 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Fallon, Peter, Correspondence, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Fallon, Peter, Poetry: “The Darker Arts,” TS (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Fallon, Peter, Poetry: “El Dorado,” TS (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Fallon, Peter, Poetry: “Herding,” TS (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Fallon, Peter, Poetry: “Killer,” TS (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Foley, Michael, Correspondence, 1972-1988 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Foley, Michael, Correspondence, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Foley, Michael, Poetry: “The Arseless Years,” and “Dossing,” TS (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Foley, Michael, Poetry: “Careers Talk,” TS (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Foley, Michael, Poetry: “I Was There,” TS (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Foley, Michael, Poetry: “The Laments of Hi Ho,” TS (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Foley, Michael, Poetry: “The World is Seldom With Us,” TS (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Foley, Michael, Drama: The Few, MS (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Foley, Michael, Prose: “Living the Job,” MS [essay] (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Foley, Michael, Prose: “The New Science Fiction,” MS [essay] (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Foley, Michael, Prose: “The Ulster Goldmine,” MS [essay] (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Foley, Michael, Prose: “Mr. Ewart Entertains,” MS [review of Be My Guest and An Imaginary Love Affair by Gavin Ewart] (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Foley, Michael, Prose: Review [untitled] of Energy to Burn by James Simmons (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Foley, Michael, Prose: Review [untitled] of The Long Summer Still to Come by James Simmons (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Foley, Michael, Prose: Review [untitled] of Night-Lines by John McGahern (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Greacen, Robert, Correspondence, 1970-1995 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Greacen, Robert, Correspondence, undated (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Greacen, Robert, Poetry: Uncle Jack (1990), TS [includes: “Uncle Jack,” “Bad Books,” “Instead of Flowers,” “Uncle George,” “Father,” “Photograph,” “Aunt Tillie,” “Cousin Willie,” “Goals,” “Miss Vincent,” “St. Andrew’s Day”]; with TLS from Greacen, 1 March 1990 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Greacen, Robert, Poetry: Ten Poems [includes: “Carnival at the River,” “Church and Covenant,” “City,” “Differential Calculus,” “Dreams, Nightmares,” “Hero,” “Oranges,” “A Stone from Buckie,” “Sunday in Co. Monaghan, 1935,” “A Wish for St. Patrick’s Day”]; with TLS from Greacen, 2 March 1990 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Greacen, Robert, Poetry: “Birthday,” TS (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Greacen, Robert, Poetry: “The Captain in Spain,” TS (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Greacen, Robert, Poetry: “Chorus from ‘Adam at Evening,’” TS (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Greacen, Robert, Poetry: “In This Dead Month,” TS (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Greacen, Robert, Poetry: “Jack! Jack!,” and “A Poet Dying,” TS; with ALS from Greacen, 23 July 1971 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Greacen, Robert, Poetry: “The Letter,” TS (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Greacen, Robert, Poetry: “Lines for a Young Lady on Her Twenty-First Birthday,” TS (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Greacen, Robert, Poetry: “The Only Emperor,” TS (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Greacen, Robert, Poetry: “Prothalamion for K. F.,” TS (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Greacen, Robert, Poetry: “Seaon and Season,” TS (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Greacen, Robert, Poetry: “Song,” TS (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Greacen, Robert, Poetry: “Wee Jimmy,” TS (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Greacen, Robert, Prose: Brief Encounters (1991) [proof of book of essays] (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Greacen, Robert, Prose: “John Gallen: A Memoir,” TS of essay (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Heaney, Seamus, Correspondence, 1971-1996 [See Subseries 1.2: Personal literary correspondence, restricted files]
    - Heaney, Seamus, Correspondence: Announcements and invitations, 1975-1996 [See Subseries 1.2: Personal literary correspondence, restricted files]
    - Heaney, Seamus, Poetry: “Christmas Eve,” [variant title: “An Ulster Twilight;” printed as Heaney family Christmas card, December 1984] (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Heaney, Seamus, Poetry: Belfast Group worksheet, 8 November 1971 [includes: Gifts of Rain, The Last Mummer, Servant Boy, The Tollund Man, Westering] (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Heaney, Seamus, Poetry: Seamus Heaney: The Incertus Years, TS (1985 reprint of 1961 pamphlet) [includes: “Reaping in Heat,” “October Thought,” “Nostalgia in the Afternoon,” “Aran,” “Song of My Man Alive,” “There’s Rosemary” (story), and Seamus Deane’s “Pause,” “To the dead in a city cemetery,” and “The Wedding”] (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - Heaney, Seamus, Poetry: “The Last Mummer,” TS [included with “Letter to an Editor” and “Servant Boy”] (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - Heaney, Seamus, Poetry: “Letter to an Editor,” TS [included with “The Last Mummer” and “Servant Boy”] (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Heaney, Seamus, Poetry: “Limbo,” TS (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - Heaney, Seamus, Poetry: “Servant Boy,” TS [included with “The Last Mummer” and “Letter to an Editor”] (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - Heaney, Seamus, Poetry: “Servant Boy,” autographed broadside (20 June 1971) [catalogued separately as part of the Special Collections Rare Book Collection]
    - Heaney, Seamus, Prose: “Seamus Heaney writes…” in Poetry Book Society Bulletin (summer 1969) (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - Heaney, Seamus, Prose: “Review of The Confessions of Proinnsias O’Toole” (1971) (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - Heaney, Seamus, Promotional material: Broadside for Field Work book-launch and reading, 15 October 1979 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - Heaney, Seamus, Printed material by Heaney [includes: “Whatever You Say, Say Nothing” (poem), “John Hume’s Derry” (article), “Secret Nests of County Derry” (article), “Kavanagh of the Parish,” (article), “Deep as England” (review of Ted Hughes’s Selected Poems), “Tradition and an Individual Talent” (review of The Hugh MacDiarmid Anthology), “A Poetic Legacy” (review of Padraic Fallon’s Poems), “Autobiographical Borings: A Selection from the Pen of Seamus Heaney”] (Box OP1)
    - Heaney, Seamus, Printed material about Heaney: Promotional and biographical material (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Heaney, Seamus, Printed material about Heaney: General articles and interviews (Box OP2)
    - Heaney, Seamus, Printed material about Heaney: Reviews [includes reviews of North, Field Work, Sweeney Astray, Station Island, Government of the Tongue, Haw Lantern, The Place of Writing, Spirit Level] (Box OP3)
    - Heaney, Seamus, Printed material about Heaney: “Time and History in Seamus Heaney's ‘In Memoriam Francis Ledwidge,” by Robert di Nicola in Eire-Ireland (21:4) 1986 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - Hewitt, John, Correspondence, 1968-1982 (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - Hewitt, John, Correspondence, 1965-1981 [between Hewitt and Alan Warner] (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Hewitt, John, Poetry: “Executives Third Tier,” MS (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - Hewitt, John, Poetry: “For a Moment of Darkness Over the Nation,” TS (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - Hewitt, John, Poetry: “The Last Spring,” TS (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - Hewitt, John, Poetry: “Legend in His Own Lifetime,” TS (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - Hewitt, John, Poetry: “This Was the Pub,” MS (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Hewitt, John, Poetry: “The Threatened Place: Winter in the Midlands,” TS (Box 8, Folder 75)
    - Hewitt, John, Poetry: “Two Artists,” TS (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - Hewitt, John, Printed material by Hewitt: “Coventry: The Tradition of Change and Continuity,” 1966 [prose pamphlet] (Box 8, Folder 77)
    - Hewitt, John, Printed material about Hewitt: John Hewitt International Summer School materials, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Hewitt, John, Printed material about Hewitt: Invitations and programs, 1977-1987 (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - Hogan, James, Correspondence, 1974-1982, including undated correspondence (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Jenkins, David, Poetry: TS poems for pamphlet proposed by Derek Mahon [includes: ALS from Mahon, 6 March 1978; and poems: “Postcard from Portrush,” “Tony Bareham,” “Homage to the lapel-badge…,” “Don’t cry for me (Ballymena),” “The Front Row,” “The Chess Lesson,” “The Snowdon Horsehoe,” “Perimeter Fence”] (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Johnston, Robert, Correspondence, 1972-1983 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Johnston, Robert, Correspondence, 1987-1993 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Johnston, Robert, Correspondence, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Johnston, Robert, Poetry: “Adelaide,” TS (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Johnston, Robert, Poetry: “Aero,” TS (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Johnston, Robert, Poetry: “Atheist’s Complaint,” TS (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Johnston, Robert, Poetry: “Autobiography,” TS (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Johnston, Robert, Poetry: “Before Sleep,” TS (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Johnston, Robert, Poetry: “Big House,” TS (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Johnston, Robert, Poetry: “In Time of Peace,” TS (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Johnston, Robert, Poetry: “In the Tower,” TS (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Johnston, Robert, Poetry: “Lovers’ Moon,” TS (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Johnston, Robert, Poetry: “New Incidents in the Life of Shelley,” TS (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Johnston, Robert, Poetry: “Scientific Fiction,” TS (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Johnston, Robert, Poetry: “Upside Down,” TS (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Johnston, Robert, Poetry: “Vegand’s Complaint,” TS (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Johnston, Robert, Prose: “The Cultural Revolution,” TS (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Johnston, Robert, Prose: “ Honest Ulsterman Press Release,” TS (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Johnston, Robert, Printed material about Johnston: Invitations and programs (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Johnston, Robert, Photograph (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Keenan, Gerard, Correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Keenan, Gerard, Correspondence, 1975-1984 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Keenan, Gerard, Correspondence, 1986, 1988, undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Keenan, Gerard, Prose: The First Chronicle of Farset, TS [novel chapters 3-14] (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Keenan, Gerard, Prose: “The H.U. Business Section,” TS [essays by “Jude the Obscure”] (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Longley, Michael, Correspondence, 1970-1977 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Longley, Michael, Correspondence, 1978-1984 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Longley, Michael, Correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Longley, Michael, Correspondence, undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Longley, Michael, Correspondence, 1977, 1990 [from Frank Ormsby] (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Longley, Michael, Correspondence, Invitations and programs (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: Gorse Fires, TS (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: Belfast Group worksheets, circa 1970-1971 [includes: To the Poets, Mountain Swim, A Nativity, Miscarriage, The North, Lares, Caravan] (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: Belfast Group worksheets, 31 January 1972 [includes: Altera Cithera, Three Posthumous Pieces, The Island, Casualty, Badger, Hedgehog, Robin, Kingfisher, The Adulterer] (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “An Amish Rug,” TS (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “Anticleia,” TS (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “Belfast to Dublin,” TS (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “Between Hovers,” TS (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “The Butchers,” TS [with ALS from Longley] (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “Cat’s Cradle,” TS (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “A Dedication,” TS (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “Detour,” TS (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “Entomology,” TS (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “Ghetto,” TS [See also ALS from Longley included with “The Butchers”] (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “Homecoming,” TS (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “Insomnia,” TS and “Phosphorescence,” TS (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “Laertes,” TS [See also ALS from Longley included with “The Butchers”] (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “A Lapwing’s Egg,” Christmas card, undated (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “A Letter to James Simmons,” TS [with ALS from Longley, 12 April 1972] (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “Peregrine,” Christmas card, undated (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “Ploughing By the Tail,” TS (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “Sea Shanty,” TS (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “Soiree,” TS (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “Spells,” TS (Box 9, Folder 56)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “Spring Tide,” TS (Box 9, Folder 57)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: “Trade Winds,” TS (Box 9, Folder 58)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry: untitled fragments, MS (Box 9, Folder 59)
    - Longley, Michael, Poetry by Julie O’Callaghan: “Naturally the Foundation Will Not Bear My Expense,” TS (Box 9, Folder 60)
    - Mahon, Derek, Correspondence, 1975-1984 (Box 9, Folder 61)
    - Mahon, Derek, Correspondence, undated (Box 9, Folder 62)
    - Mahon, Derek, Correspondence, 1969 [to James Simmons] (Box 9, Folder 63)
    - Mahon, Derek, Poetry: “Four Poems,” TS [includes: J.P. Donleavy's Dublin,” “The Graduate in Metal Box,” “Gypsies II,” “I Am Raftery”] (Box 9, Folder 64)
    - Mahon, Derek, Poetry: “Two Translations,” TS [variant title: “After Nerval”] (Box 9, Folder 65)
    - Mahon, Derek, Poetry: “The Voice,” TS translated from the French of Philippe Jaccottet [includes unsourced printed version] (Box 9, Folder 66)
    - Marcus, David, Correspondence, 1968-1969 [to James Simmons] (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Marcus, David, 1970-1978 [to Frank Ormsby] (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Matthews, Tom, Correspondence, 1970-1981 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Matthews, Tom, Correspondence, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Matthews, Tom, Poetry: Foolstop, TS pamphlet mock-up,1973 [includes: “Sibyl,” “Young Girl’s Diary,” “Robert Sat,” “Oh Teenangels,” “The Dead Saviour,” “Happy Arabia,” “Quentin Crisp,” “Poem to Edward Lear,” “The Successful Candidate,” “Juggler,” “The Cowboy Film,” “Tom’s Song,” “Adjusted,” “We Meet,” “Benign,” “Skin Trouble,” “Beef Curry,” “Restless,” “The Road Again”] (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Matthews, Tom, Poetry: “Archie Duffin,” TS (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Matthews, Tom, Poetry: “Better Days,” TS (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Matthews, Tom, Poetry: “Blessed,” “Gross Monk,” “Guest,” and “Travel Pome,” TS (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Matthews, Tom, Poetry: “Chaine of Chaine Park,” TS (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Matthews, Tom, Poetry: “Diesel Dan,” TS (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Matthews, Tom, Poetry: “Gustav the Great Explorer,” TS (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Matthews, Tom, Poetry: “On the Pomes,” TS (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Matthews, Tom, Poetry: “Pity Poor Children,” TS (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Matthews, Tom, Poetry: “Poet in the Grass,” TS (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Matthews, Tom, Poetry: “Pop Festival,” TS (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Matthews, Tom, Poetry: “Quentin Crisp,” TS (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Matthews, Tom, Poetry: “Suicide Boy,” TS (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Matthews, Tom, Poetry: “Virginian,” TS (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - McFadden, Roy, Correspondence, 1979-1981 [to Frank Ormsby] (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - McFadden, Roy, Correspondence, 1979 [from Frank Ormsby to Roy McFadden] (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - McFadden, Roy Correspondence, 1979 [from assorted editors to Roy McFadden] (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - McFadden, Roy, Poetry: “Daisymount Terrace,” TS [with TLS from Roy McFadden, 2 April 1978] (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - McFadden, Roy, Poetry: After Seymour’s Funeral, TS (1990) (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - McFadden, Roy, Poetry: Verifications, proofs (1977) (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - McFadden, Roy, Poetry: selections for Ormsby's Poets from the North of Ireland [includes: “Epithalamium,” “First Letter to an Irish Novelist,” “Stringer’s Field,” TS; with TLS from McFadden, 13 May 1979] (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - McFadden, Roy, Poetry: selections for Ormsby's Poets from the North of Ireland [includes: “Contemplations of Mary,” “From Memoirs of Chinatown: Bigamy,” “First Letter to an Irish Novelist,” “The Grand Central Hotel,” proofs; with TLS from McFadden, 21 May 1979] (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - McGuckian, Medbh, Correspondence, 1975-1980 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - McGuckian, Medbh, Correspondence, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - McGuckian, Medbh, Poetry: “After the Fire,” TS (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - McGuckian, Medbh, Poetry: “Amelia,” TS (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - McGuckian, Medbh, Poetry: “Balakhana,” TS (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - McGuckian, Medbh, Poetry: “The Bone-Setter,” TS (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - McGuckian, Medbh, Poetry: “The Cage-Cup,” TS (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - McGuckian, Medbh, Poetry: “Catching Geese,” TS (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - McGuckian, Medbh, Poetry: “The Chain Sleeper,” TS (Box 10, Folder 35)